Jonathan Hindi

IT Project Manager

11 years of working experience with small businesses and startup companies; 5 years of which have been in project management helping grow startups such as Flywheel, BuildFire, Cabulous and KaleoApps with an emphasis on mobile and web development.

Work Experience

BuildFire – IT Project Manager (May 2014 – Present)

<u>BuildFire</u> is a startup company that provides a CMS for phone applications which work on both Android and iOS using PhoneGap technology. An agile XP approach was taken for faster responses to feedback and client demands. My responsibilities are:

- Managing a team of 10 developers both remotely & locally
- Short & long term planning
- SDLC management & reporting

Featured in Businesses News Daily

- Conducting ROI Analysis
- Business synergy management
- Product development
- Designing & developing specs

KaleoApps - IT Project Manager (July 2013 - May 2014)

<u>KaleoApps</u> is a startup company which targets non-profit organizations. They provide a digital donation platform and developed mobile applications. The project started with a scrum approach for inter-dependent features which later turned into a kanban process for continued integration and faster turnaround. My responsibilities were:

- Managing a team of 12 developers remotely
- SDLC & risk management
- Breaking down tasks & budgeting
- Product development

- Designed logic work flow and UX wireframes
- Developed responsive front end interfaces
- Testing, QA, rollout & support

Flywheel - IT Project Manager (Feb 2012 - Dec 2013)

<u>Flywheel</u> is a company that provides a geo-tracking software solutions that can be implemented on any smartphone. They have been expanding rapidly and internationally with a main focus in the transportation industry. We operated under a kanban system and created native applications for both Android and iOS. My responsibilities were:

- Managing a team of 18 developers,
 split between iOS, Android and web
- Synergy management between departments & development
- Logic work flow & wireframe design
- SDLC management and reporting
- Responsive high fidelity mockups
- Front end development
- Android XML Development

Cabulous - IT Project Manager (Oct 2010 - Feb 2012)

Cabulous is a startup company which provides an automated system that mediates between cab drivers/fleets and their passengers. It also provided a dispatch system and tracker for dispatchers and fleet owners. Their main focus was developing the native applications for iOS and Android while seamlessly communicating with the tracking system. My responsibilities included:

- Managing a team of 12 developers,
 split between iOS, Android and web
- Designing logic work flow & UX wireframes
- Scrum master
- SDLC management and reporting
- Responsive high fidelity mockups
 - Front end development

LA Law Library - Communication Coordinator (Dec 2010 - Feb 2012)

<u>LALL</u> is the second largest legal library in the US. I came in when the Library was ready to completely reinvent itself from being a warehouse of books to a leader in research technology. I was responsible for:

- Creating communication strategies and marketing efforts
- Designing communication materials, both digital and print
- Organizing events such as Galas
- Web site maintenance and updates
- Developing mass email blasts
- Organizing and designing booths and communication material in events and conferences

Magnify 360 - Front End Web Developer (Sep 2010 - Dec 2010)

<u>A SEO optimization company</u> serving clients such as Intuit®, MasterCard®, netSpend™, Seagate® among others. Through their patented software they customized landing pages for SEO purposes and helped generate higher click through rates. My role included:

- Front end development
- Extraction and optimization assets
- Designing landing pages, e-banners and ads

Safe Mode Services - Owner (Aug 2009 - Dec 2013)

A business created to satisfy any technical and marketing need. Clients served:

- Vitro An advertisement agency serving clients such as: Budweiser, Land Rover, Asics
- **MadainCorp** A software service provider
- **GGothika** Gothic jewelry owned by a gold smith dealing with precise stones
- **WeNominate.com** A voting site similar to Yelp
- Top To Toe Mobile In home SPA service
- Skin Body Lounge SPA and lounge
- All Star Video Games Ecommerce site, specializing in vintage video games
- City Wide Dispatch A cab dispatcher
- Cam Caddie Wholesaler, providing camera accessories
- **Hefner Property Management** Business property management company
- Among other companies

Skills & Qualifications

Project Management

- Custom Software Development
- SDLC and risk management
- System Migrations/Integrations
- Full comprehension of methodologies and effectiveness of each

Leadership & Added Value

- Cross-functional supervision
- Team building, mentoring & stress management
- Client relations & presentation business & IT planning
- Product development
- Logic workflow design UX design

IT Project Lifecycle

- Requirements analysis
- ROI analysis
- Costing & budgeting
- Project scheduling
- Testing/QA/Rollout/Support

Skills & Technologies

- CS 6 (Photoshop, Illustrator ... etc.)
- HTML5
- CSS
- JS, JQuery
- SEM, SEO
- PhoneGap
- Microsoft Office
- Visio
- Jira
- Pivotal Tracker

Education

Project Management Professional (PMP)

(In progress - End 2014)

PMP Certifications

California State University, Northridge

2010

BS, Marketing